Guide to the Léonie Adams and William Troy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Léonie Adams and William Troy papers
1902-1980
YCAL MSS 316
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9
(13 boxes) + 2 broadside folders
The Léonie Adams and William Troy Papers consist of correspondence, writings, teaching materials, and other papers that document the personal and professional lives of both writers and teachers. The papers span the years 1902 to 1980.
Adams, Léonie, 1899-1988
Troy, William, 1903-1961
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Léonie Adams, circa 1972; Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, 1983; and Jett W. Whitehead, 2002. Gift of Glenn Horowitz, 1983; Sharon Reuter, 1986; and Bette Bonaci, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 13: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. Consult Access Services for further information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm service copies are available for Series I. General Correspondence, Lincoln Kirstein (film number 2339).
Léonie Adams
Léonie Adams was born Léonie Fuller in Brooklyn, New York, on December 9, 1899. She grew up with five siblings in a strict household until she left to attend Barnard College, from which she graduated in 1922. During her studies Adams began to write poetry and became the editor of The Measure. In 1925, she published her first collection of poetry, Those Not Elect. The book received great praise and Adams continued to write poetry while working as an editor for Wilson Publishing and The Metropolitan Museum of Art. She moved to Paris for one year in 1929 on a Guggenheim Fellowship, where she befriended H.D., regularly visited with Ford Madox Ford and Gertrude Stein, and lived with Allen Tate and his family. Her next two collections, High Falcon and Other Poems and Midsummer, were published in the same year. In 1930, she returned to New York and taught at New York University, where she met writer and teacher William Troy. The two married in 1933 and Adams published her collection of poetry, This Measure. She published no poetry for the next twenty-five years yet continued to teach poetry and was elected Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress (now known as the U.S. Poet Laureateship) in 1948.
Adams spent the rest of her career editing and teaching poetry for various institutions, including Columbia University; New York University; New Jersey College for Women (known then as Douglass College), from which she received an honorary doctoral degree in 1950; the University of Washington; the Breadloaf Writers Conference; and Sarah Lawrence College. In 1954, she won the Harriet Monroe Award from Poetry and in 1955 she won the Shelley Memorial Prize and shared the Bollingen Prize for Poems: A Selection with her friend and fellow poet, Louise Bogan. She received an Academy Fellowship from the Academy of American Poets in 1974. She died on June 27, 1988 in New Milford, Connecticut.
William Troy
William Troy was born in Chicago, Illinois on July 11, 1903 and grew up in nearby Oak Park, attending Loyola Academy for high school. At fifteen, he sold his first review to a newspaper. Upon graduating from Yale University in 1925, he taught for one year at the University of New Hampshire and then enrolled in graduate school at Columbia University. From 1929 to 1930 Troy studied at the Sorbonne and the University of Grenoble, France on a Field Service fellowship, taking a year off from a teaching position at New York University, where he taught from 1926-1935. He married poet Léonie Adams in 1933 and the two moved to Bennington, Vermont for teaching positions at Bennington College, where he also chaired the Department of Literature and Humanities. Throughout the 1930s, Troy was a regular literary and film reviewer for The Nation and through the 1940s he published essays, reviews, and a few poems in various literary journals. From 1945 to 1960, except for one year as a Fulbright Professor at the University of Bordeaux and the University of Rennes in 1955 and 1956, Troy taught at the New School University, focusing on Joyce and Shakespeare. He was a popular teacher among his students and is remembered among them as a great lecturer. Cancer of the larynx and a subsequent throat operation forced him to leave teaching in March 1960. He died on May 26, 1961. Selected Essays was published posthumously in 1967 and won the National Book Award in 1968.
Scope and Contents
The Léonie Adams and William Troy Papers contain correspondence, writings, photographs, printed materials, and other papers that document the professional and personal lives of the writers and educators Léonie Adams and William Troy. Correspondence comprises the bulk of the papers and primarily consists of correspondence with friends, colleagues, and various colleges and universities. Writings include poems, essays, literary and film reviews, drama, and other writings. Included among the writings are drafts of Adams's poetry collections and drafts of Troy's posthumous work, Selected Essays. The papers also contain professional and personal papers of Adams and Troy, including clippings by and about the authors, programs from readings, teaching notes, and other papers that record the lives of the couple. Photographs include snapshots of Adams and Troy, their friends and family, literary events, and travels. The papers span the years 1902 to 1980.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1920-1980. II. Writings, 1915-1973. III. Professional Papers, 1922-1964. IV. Photographs, circa 1920-1960. V. Personal Papers, 1902-1971.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Photographs; Authors; Adams, Léonie, 1899-1988; Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1948; Gordon, Caroline, 1895-1981; Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977; Phillips, Eleanor; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979; Troy, William, 1903-1961; Columbia University; Library of Congress; National Institute of Arts and Letters (U.S.); Oxford University Press; Rutgers University
- Correspondence, 1920-1980, undated; Series I; 4.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. Correspondence is organized into two subseries: Léonie Adams Correspondence and William Troy Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence contains personal and professional correspondence with friends, colleagues, literary publications, and various institutions.
  In Léonie Adams Correspondence, principle correspondents include Ben Belitt, Ruth Benedict, Bette Bonacci, Lee Hanna, Robert Lowell, Caroline Gordon, Eleanor Phillips, Allen Tate, William Troy, Columbia University, Library of Congress, and Rutgers University. Correspondence with colleges and universities regard Adams' teaching posts and invitations to lecture or read. Among the correspondents are notable writers, such as Kay Boyle, E.E. Cummings, Margaret Mead, Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, Theodore Roethke, Allen Tate, Louis Untermeyer, and Edmund Wilson. The subseries includes letters regarding Adams's Fulbright grant, her other awards and grants, the Bollingen Prize, her work to publish Troy's writings after his death, and her conversion to Christianity.
  Primary correspondents in the William Troy Correspondence include Léonie Adams, Ben Belitt, James Farrell, and Oxford University Press. Notable literary figures among the other correspondents include Kenneth Burke, E.E. Cummings, Ford Madox Ford, James Laughlin, Sinclair Lewis, and Allen Tate.
  Letters are incoming unless otherwise noted. Additional correspondence is located in Series II, Writings; Series III, Professional Papers; and Series V, Personal Papers.
  - Léonie Adams Correspondence
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of unidentified correspondence and correspondence regarding specific topics is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "A" general, 1942-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1959-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Charles Frederick and his wife, 1913-1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes letter from Hartley Pelletier to Adams regarding the death of Adams's father and letter from Adams to "Mrs. Rozer"
    - Adams, Josephine, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aiken, Conrad, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1933 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Allen, Robert F. Jr., 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Association of University Women, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Anderson, Lee, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Anne, Betsy, 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Armstrong, Florence, 1957 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1939-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Auden, W. H., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Aymar, Gordon, 1966 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "B" general, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bard College, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Barnard College, 1951-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bean, Marshall, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Belitt, Ben, 1936-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 20a-b)
      Includes small amount of letters written by Troy on behalf of Troy and Adams.
    - Bell, Doris, 1953-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Benedict, Ruth, 1924-1934, undated (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
      Includes outgoing letters
    - Benet, William Rose, 1933-1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bennington College (faculty), 1937-1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bennington College (students), 1943-1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Biala, Janice, 1937-1949 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1926-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bonacci, Bette, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31-34)
      Outgoing letters only
    - Border Poets of Texas, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Boston College, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Branch, Anna Hampstead, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brandeis, Irma, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Brandeis University, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference of Middlebury College, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Brooks, Cleanth, 1955 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Brooks, Gladys; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Brown, Marge, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Brown, Sue Jenkins, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bryn Mawr College, 1937-1953 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "C" general, 1934-1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Caetani, Marguerite, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Camilla, Sister, 1945-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Includes photographs of Sister Camilla
    - Campo, Vincent, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Carrithers, Jessica, 1955-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 51-53)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Cary, Carl, 1959 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Castle, Margaret, 1949 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Catholic Information Center, 1953 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Centenary College for Women, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Central State College, 1958 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Chapin School, 1953 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Chapin, Katherine Garrison, 1950-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1933, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Ciardi, John, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Cioffero, Vito, 1964 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Colum, Padraic, 1961 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Columbia University, 1942-1969 (Box 1, Folder 66-67)
    - Cooper, Philip, 1965 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Cornell, Julien, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Cummings, E. E., 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Cummings, Lois, 1931, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Cummington Press, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - "D" general, 1933-1968 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Davidson, Gustav, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Delafield, Eugene, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Deutsch, Babette, 1936-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Dutchess Community College, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - "E" general, 1939-1970 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - E.P. Dutton & Co., 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - East Texas State University, 1970 Feb 2 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Eaton, Charles, 1956 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1948-1966 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Edel, Leon, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Edman, Irwin, 1930 Feb 24 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Eliot, T. S., 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Everson, William, 1962 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - "F" general, 1931-1969 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc., 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Farrell, James T., 1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Fergusson, Francis, 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Ferris Booth Hall, 1965 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1949-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1927, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Fleming, Catherine, undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Fletcher, John Gould, 1948 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Fowlie, Wallace, 1937-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Friar, Kimon, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Frostbite, 1966 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Funk & Wagnalls Company, 1953-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - "G" general, 1932-1954 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Garrigue, Jean, December 1959 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Goll, Claire, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Gordon, Caroline, 1954-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 104-105)
    - Empty folder (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Gray, Harold; Gray, Lenore, 1938-1959 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Gunn, Louise, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - "H" general, 1937-1973 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - H. W. Wilson Company, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Hamilton College, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Hanna, Lee (Josephson), 1920-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 112-114)
    - Hogue, Caroline (Mrs. Richard), 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Holland, Louise, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Holt, Guy, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Horizon, 1959 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Howes, Barbara, 1949-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Hudson Review, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1966 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Humphries, Rolfe, 1955 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Hunter College of the City of New York, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Hyman, Stanley Edgar, 1951-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - "I" general, 1954-1970 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Ignatow, David, 1968 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Indiana University Writers' Conference, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - "J" general, 1937-1968 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Jeremy, Sister Mary, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - John Day Company, 1930-1951 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - John-Martin-Portley, Gregory, undated (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - "K" general, 1934-1966 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Kizer, Carolyn, 1961-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Koch, Vivienne, undated (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - "L" general, 1911, 1949-1973 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Lachenschmidt, Lydia, 1966 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Langland, Joseph, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Lappe, Esther Everett, 1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - League of American Writers, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Lennon, Florence Becker, undated (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Levine, Don Eric, undated (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Lewis, Janet, undated (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Library of Congress, 1948-1969 (Box 2, Folder 144-145)
    - Limited Editions Club, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Loggins, Vernon, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1948-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 148-149)
    - Luening, Otto, 1951 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - "M" general, 1940-1972 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Maloy, Miriam C., 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Mandel, David, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Manville, Margot, 1931, undated (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Marx, Emily, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Maynard, Theodore, 1926 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - McBryde, Robert M. & Co., 1931-1945 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - McClearey, Dorothy, undated (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - McCord, David, 1960 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Mead, Margaret, 1930-1968 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Merrill, Beverly, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Meyerson, Edward, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Miller, Arthur, undated (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Montgomery Art Guild, 1971 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1948-1960 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Moore, Merrill, Jun 30, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth, undated (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Morley, Hilda, 1952-1967 (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1946 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Moyles, Donald, 1966-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Murphy, James P.J., 1948-1959 (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - "N" general, 1933-1962 (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Nassau Community College, 1966 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - The Nation, 1932-1939 (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - National Book Award, 1952-1967 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - National Broadcasting Company, Sept 1, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - National Council of Catholic Men, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1949-1971 (Box 2, Folder 178-179)
    - National Poetry Foundation, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Nemerov, Howard, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 181)
    - The New Republic, 1936, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 182)
    - New School University, 1950-1962 (Box 2, Folder 183)
    - New York Public Library, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 184)
    - New York State University College, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 185)
    - New York University, 1964 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 186)
    - "O" general, undated (Box 2, Folder 187)
    - Oden, Gloria C., 1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 188)
    - O'Gorman, Ned, 1967, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 189)
    - Olivet College, 1938 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 190)
    - Olson, Elder, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 191)
    - "P" general, 1948-1972 (Box 2, Folder 192)
    - P.E.N., Jun 9 1952 (Box 2, Folder 193)
    - Pannel, Franny, 1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 194)
    - Parker, Lockie, 1932-1955 (Box 2, Folder 195)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1937, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 196)
    - Pettinella, Dora, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 197-198)
    - Phillips, Eleanor, 1926-1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 199-202)
    - Poetry, 1930, 1939-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 203)
    - Poetry Center, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 204)
    - Poetry Society of America, 1961, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 205)
    - Poetry Society of Virginia, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 206)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1949, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - Princeton University, 1950 February 17 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Purdue University, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - Quarterly Review of Literature, 1943, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - "R" general, 1938-1972 (Box 3, Folder 212)
    - Ratner, Louise (Rosenblatt?), 1937-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - Richman, Robert, 1949 October 22 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Riggs, Lynn, 1951 Feb 1 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - Roethke, Theodore, 1943-1965 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - Roth, Henry, undated (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - Roy, Yvonne (Mrs. Porter), 1946-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - Rutgers University, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 219-220)
    - Rutgers University Press, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 221-223)
    - "S" general, 1923-1970 (Box 3, Folder 224)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 225)
    - Saturday Review of Literature, 1933-1947 (Box 3, Folder 226)
    - Sarot, Ellin, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 227)
    - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 228)
    - Seattle University, 1960 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 229)
    - Shapiro, Karl, 1949-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 230)
    - Sherrill, Mrs. Robert Clay, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - Sigbert Mohn Verlag, May 5, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 232)
    - Simon, Joan (Lewisohn), 1943-1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 233)
    - Smith, Willa, 1952-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 234)
    - Smith, William Jay, 1961, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 235)
    - Snodgress, Annie, 1951-1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 236)
    - Southern Review, 1935, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 237)
    - Spencer, Theodore, Oct 25, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 238)
    - Speyer, Leonora, undated (Box 3, Folder 239)
    - Stewart, Helen, 1943-1971, undated (Box 3, Folder 240)
    - Swan, Emmy, 1937-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 241)
    - Swarthmore College, undated (Box 3, Folder 242)
    - Swartz, Roberta Teale, 1954 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 243)
    - Swenson, May, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 244)
    - "T" general, 1938-1971 (Box 3, Folder 245)
    - Tate, Allen, 1932-1972 (Box 3, Folder 246-247)
    - Taylor, Peter, undated (Box 3, Folder 248)
    - Thorp, Willard, 1949, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 249)
    - Torrence, Ridgeby, 1921-1933 (Box 3, Folder 250)
    - Trinity College, 1959 -1960 (Box 3, Folder 251)
    - Troy, William, 1931-1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 252-253a)
    - Turnbull, Andrew, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 254)
    - "U" general, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 255)
    - Unicorn Press, 1968 August 11 (Box 3, Folder 256)
    - University of Bridgeport, 1968 Dec 9 (Box 3, Folder 257)
    - University of Buffalo, 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 258)
    - University of California, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 259)
    - University of Chicago, 1937-1957 (Box 3, Folder 260)
    - University of Kentucky, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 261)
    - University of Michigan, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 262)
    - University of Maine, 1961 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 263)
    - University of Washington, 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 264-265)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1930-1970 (Box 3, Folder 266)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1928-1961 (Box 3, Folder 267)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1948, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 268)
    - Vidal, Amparo R., 1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 269)
    - Villa, Jose Garcia, 1954 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 270)
    - "W" general, 1933-1968 (Box 3, Folder 271)
    - Walton, Eda Lou, 1930-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 272-273)
    - Warren, R.P., 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 274)
    - Wednesday Club, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 275)
    - Wellesley College, 1952 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 276)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 277)
    - Wheeler, Tom, 1958, 1973, undated (Box 3, Folder 278)
    - Wheelock, John Hall, 1932-1971 (Box 3, Folder 279)
    - William Sloane Associates, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 280-281)
    - Williams, Florence, 1953-1963 (Box 3, Folder 282)
    - Williams, Oscar, 1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 283)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 284)
    - Wing, Camella, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 285)
    - Winnick, Harriet, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 286)
    - Wolf, Jerry, 1965 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 287)
    - Wolf, Marty, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 288)
    - Wood, Eileen, 1939, undated (Box 3, Folder 289)
    - Worth, Kathryn, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 290)
    - "Y" general, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 291)
    - Yaddo, 1936-1964 (Box 3, Folder 292)
    - Yale University, 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 293)
    - Yousseff, Ellen, 1947 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 294)
    - Zabel, Morton D., 1934-1957 (Box 3, Folder 295)
    - Unidentified, 1913-1967 (Box 3, Folder 296-297)
    - Holiday cards, 1947-1971, undated (Box 4, Folder 298)
    - Correspondence filed by subject
      - Fulbright grant, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 299-300)
        Includes printed material on travel grant to lecture in American Studies
      - Various awards and grants, 1954-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 301)